Leonard Everett Fisher Papers
© 2010 University of Connecticut
- Series IV: Audiovisual materials, undated, [19--?] -1997
  - Subseries A: Audio cassettes, 19-- -1981
    - Conversation for 6 artists [sound recording]: paint a still life / L.E. Fisher and Charles M. Daugherty. Fisher discusses working on still lifes, 1976 (Other Audio 879)
    - Conversation corner - WJER Radio [sound recording]: Leonard Everett Fisher. Recorded in Ohio. Fisher discusses his career as an illustrator including his winning the Pulitzer Painting Fellowship. He also discusses the importance of encouraging children to read, 1987 March 19 (Other Audio 880)
    - Fisher, Leonard Everett [sound recording]: [two speeches]. [Side] A. Commencement address: Paier School of Art, 6/5/71 -- [Side] B. Seminar: National Art Education Association, Hilton Hotel, New York, Apr. 7, 1972. Seminar speech: Fisher discusses the more destructive impulses of creative artists in response to the seminars topic of "Men who create do not destroy", 1971-1972 (Other Audio 881)
    - L. E. Fisher: [two radio interviews] [Side] A and B. Norwalk stamp club: Radio WNLK, 11/28/72, 9:05-9:55 PM -- [Side] B WNYC-FM (New York): the world of children's literature, 1-22-73, 4-4:30 PM/ 1-27-73, 8-8:30 PM. (WNLK) Fisher discusses his career as an illustrator, especially his work designing postage stamps. (WNYC) Augusta Baker reads from Fisher's Death of the Evening Star and interviews Leonard Fisher about the book, his interest in American history and its reflection in his books, his work on stamp designs and his career in general, [1972-1973] (Other Audio 882)
    - Books for children: Eve Merriam/Leonard E. Fisher. Marina Del Rey, Ca.: Audio Stats, 1981. Recorded 12/21/81 at an awards ceremony at the 71st Annual Convention of the National Council for Teachers of English in Boston (Other Audio 883)
    - L. E. Fisher: Imperial interview. Probably recorded in Fisher's home in Westport, Connecticut, and broadcast on a Norwalk radio station. Fisher on his book series on colonial craftsman, the origin of the idea, how he does his research, and how his does his drawings. He briefly talks about his first published work, [1968?] (Other Audio 890)
    - Stories of Latin America / [produced by Westport Communications Group, Inc.]. [New York]: Random House Educational Media. Table of Contents: Set 1. [1] Lora, Lorita / by Anico Surany. 52 fr. [2] Monsieur Jolicoeur's umbrella / by Anico Surany. 53 fr. [3] A jungle jumble / by Anico Surany. 57 fr. Set 2. [2] Ride the cold wind / by Anico Surany, 50 fr. [3] The golden frog / by Anico Surany, 45 fr. [4] The burning mountain / by Anico Surany, 45 fr., 1976-1977 (Other Audio 894)
    - Midwife's Apprentice, 1994 (Other 1997-0064.ac1)
    - Acceptance Speeches, 1994 (Other 1997-0064.ac2)
  - Subseries B: Film strips, 1976-1977
    - Stories of Latin America/ [produced by Westport Communications Group, Inc.]. [New York]: Random House Educational Media. Film strips: col.; 35 mm. Adaptations of children's stories, designed to provide insights into the people and culture of Latin America. See also Audio 894 for accompanying sound, 1976-1977
      - The burning mountain / by Anico Surany, 45 fr. (Other 1997-0064.mp1)
      - The golden frog / by Anico Surany, 45 fr. (Other 1997-0064.mp2)
      - A jungle jumble / by Anico Surany. 57 fr. (Other 1997-0064.mp3)
      - Lora, Lorita / by Anico Surany. 52 fr. (Other 1997-0064.mp4)
      - Monsieur Jolicoeur's umbrella / by Anico Surany. 53 fr. (Other 1997-0064.mp5)
      - Ride the cold wind / by Anico Surany, 50 fr. (Other 1997-0064.mp6)
  - Subseries C: VHS videocassettes, 1986-1997
    - University magazine: activities on and about the Central Missouri State University: [Children's Literature Festival episode, aired March 29, 1994] / production of KMOS-TV; executive producer, Don Peterson. [Warrensburg, Mo.: Central Missouri State University, 1994] Stories include a profile of Kildip Rampal, a professor of mass communications at CMSU, and his studies on the media in Taiwan; visits to the CMSU Children's Literature Festival by author Jean Fritz and illustrator Leonard Everett Fisher; the CMSU rugby team; profile of CMSU student Terri Swopes, a CMSU student who juggles 3 part time jobs, caring for two kids, and attending classes at CMSU; dramatic adaptation of the story of Alladin by the CMSU Children's Theater (Other Video 133)
    - Middle gate happenings- 1986-87: Guest author- Leonard Everett Fisher [1986] At an unidentified elementary school, Fisher signs books for children, and then tells about some of the techniques he uses in illustrating his books. He also talks about how his children's books are made (Other Video 134)
    - Crosstalk: [interview with Leonard Everett Fisher]. Fisher discusses his career including his illustration work on historical subjects. He also talks about the distinction between his illustration work and cartoons, 1989 (Other Video 135)
    - Leonard Everett Fisher: WCYB-TV noon show interview. In a short news segment, Fisher talks about how he started writing books, 1995 (Other 136)
    - Leonard Everett Fisher. Leonard Everett Fisher talks about his design and advisory work on stamps and his meeting with President William Clinton, 1997 (Other Video 137)
    - Leonard Everett Fisher: [lecture at meeting for] NEEMA. Fisher talks about his conception of history and historical writing and its purpose, 1990 (Other Video 140)
    - LEF: Denton Ave. School, New Hyde Park, NY. Fisher talks about his work designing stamps and shows his Sleepy Hollow stamp design. He also illustrates the process of constructing a book, 1991 (Other Video 139)
    - LEF: Feb. 26, 1988, WLIO-TV News, Lima, Ohio. In a very brief interview, Fisher talks about for whom he writes and illustrates his books (Other Video 138)
  - Subseries D: Reel to reel tapes, 1969
    - Leonard Everett Fisher. [Kankakee, Ill.]: Imperial International Learning. 1 sound tape reel: 3 3/4 ips; 5 in., 1/4 in. tape. Meet the Authors, LI4608, 1969 (Other 1997-0064.rr1)
  - Subseries E: Videoreels, undated
    - Fisher, L.E., undated (Other 1997-0064.vr1)
  - Subseries F: U-matic videocassettes, 1978, 1983
    - Leonard Everett Fisher: Live at One the Fairfield Exchange. Cablevision of Connecticut, Channel 12, 1983 September 27 (Other 1997-0064.vr2)
    - Leonard Everett Fisher: profile of an illustrator. Cleveland, Ohio: WVIZ, 1978 November 17 (Other 1997-0064.vr3)